Guide to the Richard Benson Sewall Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- Additional materials, 1830-1999; Accession 2018-M-0051
  - Lectures and courses, 1926-1993
    - Coursework
      - English 61 Tragedy
        - The Roots of Elizabethan Tragedy, 1947–1957 (Box 21, Folder 9)
        - Sartre, Jean-Paul, 1949–1957 (Box 21, Folder 10)
        - Shakespeare histories, 1950–1961 (Box 21, Folder 11)
        - Shakespeare's Tragic Vision, 1964 (Box 21, Folder 12-13)
        - Sidelights, 1943–1976 (Box 21, Folder 14)
        - Sound and Fury, 1950–1972 (Box 21, Folder 15)
        - Stoppard, Tom, circa 1960s (Box 22, Folder 1)
        - Syllabus, 1940–1977 (Box 22, Folder 2-4)
        - Tambarlaine, 1951–1969 (Box 22, Folder 5)
        - The Tempest, 1962–1968 (Box 22, Folder 6)
        - Term essay topics, 1949–1984 (Box 22, Folder 7)
        - Tragedy in Eclipse, 1976–1980 (Box 22, Folder 8)
        - Troilus and Cressda, 1961 (Box 22, Folder 9)
        - Webster, John, 1950–1975 (Box 22, Folder 10)
        - Williams, Tennessee, 1948–1981 (Box 22, Folder 11)
      - English 77a daily themes, 1965–1983 (Box 23, Folder 1)
      - English 157
        - 18th century Benjamin Franklin, 1957–1965 (Box 23, Folder 2)
        - Anderson, Sherwood, circa 1950s (Box 23, Folder 3)
        - Bibliography, 1956–1966 (Box 23, Folder 4)
        - Crane, Hart, circa 1950s (Box 23, Folder 5)
        - Emerson, Ralph Waldo, 1957–1965 (Box 23, Folder 6)
        - Irving, Washington, 1956–1958 (Box 23, Folder 7)
        - Longfellow, Henry Wadsworth, 1956 (Box 23, Folder 8)
        - Masters, 1960 (Box 23, Folder 9)
        - Poe, Edgar Allan, 1956–1965 (Box 23, Folder 10)
        - The Puritans, 1956–1961 (Box 23, Folder 11)
        - Shakespeare stage, 1953 (Box 23, Folder 12)
        - Tempest, 1968 (Box 23, Folder 13)
        - Thoreau, Henry David, 1956–1962 (Box 23, Folder 14)
        - Warren, Robert Penn, 1959 (Box 23, Folder 15)
        - Whitman, Walt, 1956–1973 (Box 23, Folder 16)
        - Wolfe, Tom, 1954 (Box 23, Folder 17)
      - Grades
        Conditions Governing Access
        Student records are restricted until 2060 as established by Yale Corporation regulations http://web.library.yale.edu/mssa/collections/research-use-of-yale-university-archives.
        - Gradebooks, 1934–1950 (Box 24, Folder 1-4)
        - Gradebooks, 1948–1975 (Box 25, Folder 1-4)
        - Gradebooks, 1976–1978 (Box 26, Folder 1)
        - Stevens, Wallace, 1974-1985 (Box 26, Folder 2)
  - Research files and writings, 1830-1997
    - Emily Dicksinon
      - Adams, Frank, 1971 (Box 27, Folder 1)
      - Aushander, Joseph, poetry, circa 1970s (Box 27, Folder 2)
      - Baker, Russell, growing up, 1983 (Box 27, Folder 3)
      - Bibliography of Emily Dickinson reviews, 1958 (Box 27, Folder 4)
      - Bolton-Smith, Anne, The Language of Loneliness, 1963 (Box 27, Folder 5)
      - Book chapter on Helen Hunt Jackson, circa 1970s (Box 27, Folder 6)
      - Burkert on Emily Dickinson, circa 1970s (Box 27, Folder 7)
      - Clark, Connie, 1985 (Box 27, Folder 8)
      - Cody, John, manuscript review, 1965–1971 (Box 27, Folder 9)
      - Dandurand, Karen, notes, 1984 (Box 27, Folder 10)
      - Deutsch, Babette, 1958–1973 (Box 27, Folder 11)
      - Emily Dickinson and Henry David Thoreau, circa 1960s (Box 27, Folder 12)
      - Emily Dickinson, exotropia in eye, 1982 (Box 27, Folder 13)
      - Emily Dickinson, "Eyes be Blind, Heart be Still: A New Perspective on the Emily Dickinson Eye Problem", 1979–1983 (Box 27, Folder 14)
      - Emily Dickinson, notes on her poetic method, tone, metaphor, and audience, 1966 (Box 27, Folder 15)
      - Emily Dickinson Head On, The Folger Library, 1986 (Box 27, Folder 16)
      - Emily Dickinson, "Science and the Poet: Emily Dickinson's Herbarium and the Clue Divine", 1992 (Box 27, Folder 17)
      - Emily Dickinson's Perfect Audience: Helen Hunt Jackson, 1997 (Box 28, Folder 1)
      - Emily Dickinson's White Robes, 1963 (Box 28, Folder 2)
      - Explications of Emily Dickinson poems, 1961 (Box 28, Folder 3)
      - Finch, A.R.C., on Emily Dickinson's pentameters, circa 1980s (Box 28, Folder 4)
      - Folger-Weisbuch, 1986 (Box 28, Folder 5)
      - Frye, Northrop, 1963 (Box 28, Folder 6)
      - Griffith, Clark, 1964 (Box 28, Folder 7)
      - Hall, Mary Lee, quitclaim deed, 1892 (Box 28, Folder 8)
      - Himelhoch, Myra, circa 1960s (Box 28, Folder 9)
      - Howard, Richard, circa 1960s (Box 28, Folder 10)
      - Howard, William, 1957 (Box 28, Folder 11)
      - Jobes, Katharine Taylor, 1961 (Box 28, Folder 12)
      - Johnson, Ken, 1964 (Box 28, Folder 13)
      - Jones, Rowena Revis, 1983 (Box 28, Folder 14)
      - The Letters of Emily Dickinson, review by Thomas Johnson and Theodora Ward, 1958–1961 (Box 28, Folder 15)
      - The Life of Emily Dickinson, prepublication review, 1976 (Box 28, Folder 16)
      - Lindberg-Seyersted, Brita, 1968 (Box 28, Folder 17)
      - List of books found in the home of Emily Dickinson, Houghton Library, 1950 (Box 28, Folder 18)
      - MacLeish, Archibald, 1967 (Box 28, Folder 19)
      - Martz, Louis, review, 1958 (Box 28, Folder 20)
      - McLean, Sydney, 1934 (Box 28, Folder 21)
      - Miller, Betty, circa 1970s (Box 28, Folder 22)
      - Miller, Ruth, The News from New England, circa 1980s (Box 28, Folder 23)
      - Moore, Marianne, review of Mabel Lewis Todd's Letters of Emily Dickinson, 1931 (Box 28, Folder 24)
      - Notebook with Sewall's notes on authors, circa 1930s (Box 28, Folder 25)
      - Photographs from The Life of Emily Dickinson, circa 1830s-1973 (Box 28, Folder 26)
      - Photographs from The Life of Emily Dickinson, circa 1830s-1973 (Box 29, Folder 1)
      - Photographs of Joseph Lyman, circa 1970s (Box 29, Folder 2)
      - Pollak, Vivian, article review, 1973 (Box 29, Folder 3)
      - Porter, David, reviews, 1983 (Box 29, Folder 4)
      - The Readers Encyclopedia of American History, article on Emily Dickinson, 1989 (Box 29, Folder 5)
      - Reviews by Ruth Miller, Robert Weisbuch, and Richard Levin, 1986–1992 (Box 29, Folder 6)
      - Rich, Adrienne, 1975 (Box 29, Folder 7)
      - Rourke, C., circa 1980s (Box 29, Folder 8)
      - Sherwood, Robert, review, 1966 (Box 29, Folder 9)
      - Stamm, Edith, 1963–1967 (Box 29, Folder 10)
      - Sullivan, William, 1965 (Box 29, Folder 11)
      - Tripp, Raymond, circa 1980s (Box 29, Folder 12)
      - Van Doren, Mark, circa 1960s (Box 29, Folder 13)
      - Violence and abstraction in Emily Dickinson, 1958 (Box 29, Folder 14)
      - Visions and Voices: Emily Dickinson, 1985 (Box 29, Folder 15)
      - Walsh, John Evangelist, 1971 (Box 29, Folder 16)
      - Warren, Austin, 1957 (Box 29, Folder 17)
      - Weisbuch, Robert, 1973 (Box 29, Folder 18)
      - Whicher, George F., "The Voice of a Poet" introduction, 1980 (Box 30, Folder 1)
      - Wilder, Thornton, 1952 (Box 30, Folder 2)
    - General
      - Adams, Henry, 1965 (Box 30, Folder 3)
      - Bibliography, Rousseau pieces, 1937–1951 (Box 30, Folder 4)
      - Bibliography, tragedy essay reviews, 1954–1964 (Box 30, Folder 5)
      - Collins, Bud, book review, 1989 (Box 30, Folder 6)
      - Dreiser, Theodore, 1961 (Box 30, Folder 7)
      - Education reviews, 1951–1969 (Box 30, Folder 8)
      - Essays sent to Dean Swift, circa 1940s (Box 30, Folder 9)
      - Extraordinary Lives reviews, 1986 (Box 30, Folder 10)
      - Great figures in world literature, 1959 (Box 30, Folder 11)
      - James, Henry, 1953–1965 (Box 30, Folder 12)
      - Jung, Carl, 1963–1964 (Box 30, Folder 13)
      - Nuclear freeze, 1982–1983 (Box 30, Folder 14)
      - Olson, Elder, 1961 (Box 31, Folder 1)
      - Pearson, Norman Holmes, 1952–1953 (Box 31, Folder 2)
      - Remembering Denny by Calvin Trillin, review, 1993 (Box 31, Folder 3)
      - Rousseau in England in the Eighteenth Century, circa 1950s-1960s (Box 31, Folder 4-6)
      - Selzer, Richard, review, 1976 (Box 31, Folder 7)
      - Sewall, Richard, graduate student research notes, 1931 (Box 31, Folder 8)
      - Sewall, Richard, writings and reviews, 1954–1961 (Box 31, Folder 9)
      - Steiner, George, 1961 (Box 31, Folder 10)
      - Tragedy, new chapters, 1949–1996 (Box 31, Folder 11)
      - Tragedy notebook, circa 1950s (Box 32, Folder 1)
      - The Tragic Form, 1961 (Box 32, Folder 2)
      - The Tragic Theater, circa 1970s (Box 32, Folder 3)
      - Tragic Themes, 1954 (Box 32, Folder 4)
      - The Vision of Tragedy article and reviews, 1956–1961 (Box 32, Folder 5)
      - Wharton, Lyman, 1966 (Box 32, Folder 6)
    - Strong family
      - Strong, Alvah, writings, circa 1900s (Box 32, Folder 7)
      - Strong, Augustus Hopkins, 1861–1981 (Box 32, Folder 8-9)
      - Strong, Augustus Hopkins, Reminiscenes of Early Rochester, 1916 (Box 32, Folder 10)
      - Strong, Charles A., letters to family, 1879 (Box 32, Folder 11)
      - Strong, Charles A., letters to family, 1881–1885 (Box 33, Folder 1-3)
      - Strong family, 1958–1980 (Box 33, Folder 4)
      - Strong family correspondence, 1921–1983 (Box 33, Folder 5-6)
      - Strong, John Henry, 1957–1960 (Box 33, Folder 7)
  - Yale University, 1934-1994
    - Alumni talks, 1955–1967 (Box 34, Folder 1)
    - Brewster, Kingman, 1964–1965 (Box 34, Folder 2)
    - Calhoun College, the fifth year, 1937–1938 (Box 34, Folder 3)
    - Curricular Development at Yale, New Haven Alumni talk, 1966 (Box 34, Folder 4)
    - Ezra Stiles College, 1966–1974 (Box 34, Folder 5)
    - Ezra Stiles College cornerstone speech, 1961 (Box 34, Folder 6)
    - Ezra Stiles College Fellows, 1970–1982 (Box 34, Folder 7)
    - Ezra Stiles College senior dinner, 1986 (Box 34, Folder 8)
    - Freshman year, 1947–1953 (Box 34, Folder 9)
    - McClure, James, 1992–1994 (Box 34, Folder 10)
    - Scholars of the House program, 1961–1987 (Box 34, Folder 11)
    - Spiro, Howard, The Program for Humanities in Medicine advisory board, 1984 (Box 34, Folder 12)
    - Starlight festival, 1977–1978 (Box 34, Folder 13)
    - "An Unofficial Tour of Yale", American Heritage, 1991 (Box 34, Folder 14)
    - Yale Alumni Seminar, William Faulkner, 1959 (Box 34, Folder 15)
    - Yale faculty, up the ladder and testimonials, 1941–1976 (Box 34, Folder 16)
    - Yale Graduate School, 1934–1976 (Box 34, Folder 17)
    - Yale Parents Commission, 1963–1966 (Box 34, Folder 18)
  - Personal, 1898-1994
    - Biography, 1968 (Box 35, Folder 1)
    - Boat bills, 1939–1946 (Box 35, Folder 2)
    - Boat purchase, 1939–1947 (Box 35, Folder 3)
    - Cambyses poetry, 1975 (Box 35, Folder 4)
    - Deconstruction, 1980–1992 (Box 35, Folder 5)
    - Funny stuff, circa 1970s-1980s (Box 35, Folder 6)
    - Resumes, 1965 (Box 35, Folder 7)
    - Russell, Robert, Northminster United Presbyterian Church, 1972 (Box 35, Folder 8)
    - Schneider, Mark, 1981 (Box 35, Folder 9)
    - Sewall, Grenville Strong, eulogy, 1992 (Box 35, Folder 10)
    - Sewall, Mathilde, 1966–1975 (Box 35, Folder 11)
    - Sketch of the Public and Private Life of Samuel Miles Hopkins of Salem, Connecticut, 1898 (Box 35, Folder 12)